



Technical Lead seeking roles in Application Development, Application Design, Release Management, Software Development, Product Development, Service Delivery, Resource Allocation, Failure Analysis, Contingency Planning, Quality Management, Risk Management



Current Designation: Technical Lead Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Info Vision Labs Pvt. Ltd. Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: Singapore, United Arab Emirates (UAE), United

States (US)

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Technical Lead, Team Lead/Tech Lead, Application Development, Application Design, Release Management, Software Development, Product Development, Service Delivery, Resource Allocation, Failure

Analysis, Contingency Planning, Quality Management, Risk Management

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

responsiveness to new feature requests.

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

Competent Professional with over 8.11 years of relevant Java/J2EE experience in aligning development to business strategy in order to deliver structured, efficient, sustainable and adaptable IT solutions in line with the business needs Identified architectural development improvements resulting in increased developer efficiency, product reliability, and

Skilled in Product Strategy, Design, Full Stack, Product Development, Agile and DevOps transformation, Cloud Migration and

Technology Modernization.

Led service delivery, leadership and implementation by applying best practices to achieve zero surprise operations and delivery

excellence in industries.

Implemented and created the full life cycle process for large-scale software development in Finance, Banking, Card Processing,

Implemented and created the full life cycle process for large-scale software development in Finance, Banking, Card Processing E-payment and Telecom services.

Work Experience

Info Vision Labs Pvt. Ltd. as Technical Lead

May 2019 to Till Date

Competent Professional with over 8.11 years of relevant Java/J2EE experience in aligning architecture to business strategy in order to deliver structured, efficient, sustainable and adaptable IT solutions in line with the business needs.

Implemented and created the full life cycle process for large-scale software development in Finance, Banking, Card Processing, E-payment and Telecom services.

Built Web/Enterprise applications using Java, J2ee, JSP, Servlet, JDBC, Struts, Hibernate, Spring, Web-services(REST-JAX-RS/SOAP-JAX-WS, Spring REST) with Jersey, Apache Axis2/CXF and JSON, JAXB, Spring Boot, Spring Reactive, Micro services(Eureka Client, Feign Client), JPA, JMS 1.0, Java Mail API.

Knowledge of Design Patterns, Angular JS, Angular 6, Node JS, React JS, SQL, PLSQL and CQL (Cassandra Query Language), GraphiQL (Graph Query Language).

Expertise in 1st, 2nd & 3rd level on call rotation production.

Atos India Pvt. Ltd. as System Analyst

Jul 2015 to Jan 2019

In Atos India Pvt. Ltd., as System Analyst Project Name: Atos Worldline(Merchant Extranet)

Duration: Jul'15-Jan'19

Environment: JDK1.6, Servlet, Webservices (Spring-REST), JPA, AngularJs, NodeJs, Oracle, spring (IOC, AOP, Security-Web), Postman, Apache Tomcat, Maven, SonarQube, Eclipse IDE, JIRA, VsCode

Description: Worldline specializes in electronic payment end-to-end services for critical electronic transactions (issuing, acquiring, payment solutions, terminals and card processing) services for financial markets as well as eCS (eServices for customers, citizens and communities). Worldline India provides end-to-end services for electronic transaction in India. It focuses on electronic payment services for banks, merchants and government and activation; point-of-sale (PoS) terminal procurement supply and installation and merchant training. It presents credit, debit and prepaid cards application, issuance and transaction processing, currency conversion, fraud and risk management and internet and mobile payment services. The company caters to banking, financial services, energy, utilities and retail, hospitality, transport and healthcare sectors. Worldline creates and manages e/m-services for customer portfolios, operating as a digital services provider that helps businesses and consumers to capitalize on digital ecosystems to deliver batter commercial performance and business efficiency for our customers. Worldline is a rapidly expanding global player and the European leader in business and payments transactional services. It provide business enabling IT services and industry expertise to support our customers top line growth through innovation and by enhancing their competitiveness.

Capgemini India Pvt Ltd as Consultant

Oct 2012 to Jun 2015

In Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd. Duration: Oct'12 - Jun'15 Role: Consultant

Project Name: Discover Financial Services (Diners Club International)

Environment: JDK1.6, Servlet, Java Beans, Spring IOC, JSF, HTML, Prime Faces, JPA, RSA IDE, WebLogic, Maven,

Description: Discover Financial Services, Inc. is and American financial services company, which issues the Discover Card and operates the Discover and Pulse networks. Discover stated that the Diners Club Network, which is a major network outside North America, will be merged with the Discover Network, a major network in North America creating an international network for Discover Network Cards and Diners Club Cards. Diners Club cards will continue to be issued by Diners Club International licenses. Discover Bank has no plans on issuing Diners Club branded cards itself. Diners Club is a charge card company in the world that established an idea of a self-sufficient company producing credit cards for travel and entertainment. Diners Club International and its franchises service high net, affluent and well-travelled individuals from around the globe. Diners Club created what would later be dubbed the "travel and entertainment" (T&E) card market, which focused on frequent travelers with a substantial income to pay for other high-value charges. As these customers had no need to pay for purchases over time, these cards required that the entire balance of the bill be paid upon receipt. This type of account is known today as a charge card.

Pyramid IT Consulting India Pvt Itd as Senior Software Developer Jan 2011 to Sep 2011

Sr.Software Developer

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from Manipal University in 2004

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Oracle Certified Java SE7 Programmer (IZ0-803 & IZ0-804)

MS Azure AZ-900 Certification

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Windows, Linux & Ubuntu	
Core Java(1.8), Python	
AWT/Swing, PL/SQL, CQL	
HTML, JavaScript, CSS, XML, Angular	
Ajax, TypeScript, NodeJs, JSON, JAXB	

122		

1/22/2021	nttps://ircesearch.naukn.com/previ	omprima todarno : an	umo 014 1002	70007 0020 1040 107 2010401 10001
JDBC, JSP,	, Java Beans, Servlets			
EJB 2.0, JN	/IS 1.0, Java Mail API			
Apache Tor	mcat,YAML, Jenkins			
Weblogic, J	Boss, Websphere, Glassfish			
Eclipse, Ne	tBeans, STS, RSA/RAD			
WSAD, VS	Code , Ant, Maven, Gradle			
HP Quality	Center, Sonarqube, Postman			
Swagger, S	oapUI, Talend API Tester			
SVN, Datas	Stax DevCenter, Docker			
GIT Lab/GI	T Hub, Putty, Toad	4.0	2020	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Tortoise, Ra	ational Clear Case,JIRA Agile	4.0	2020	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Jakarta Stru	uts, Hibernate, Spring	4.0	2020	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JSF, JPA, S	Spring Boot, Spring Reactive	4.0	2020	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
MS-Access	, MySql, Oracle, DB2	4.0	2020	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
PostgresSq	I, Cassandra, GraphiQL	4.0	2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
REST(JAX-	-RS), SOAP(JAX-WS)	5.0	2020	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SpringRest	, Spring Boot	5.0	2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Micro Servi	ces specification	5.0	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
German	Beginner			
Hindi	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time